There are more
Bash features that matter.
For instance, there is Alias. Alias
allows you to define your own commands.
So if you would type
Alias, list is LS l,
then you have defined your
new command, which is list.
You can use Alias without arguments to
request a list of aliases that are
currently set when set from the
command line. An alias is not persistent.
If you want to make them persistent,
you need to put them in the
ETC profile or one of the
related files. We'll talk about those later.
Bash also works with keyboard shortcuts,
and these keyboard shortcuts make working
with Bash a lot easier.
Control L will clear your screen.
Control U will wipe the current command line. Control
A will move the cursor to the beginning of
the line, and Control E is doing the
opposite. It moves to the end of the line.
Control C is the break, it interrupts the current
process. And Control D is a generic exit command.
Let me show
you some of this.
That was Control L to start with. I
do it in conscious. I wasn't even thinking about
it. Here we have Alias, which is showing
all the aliases that exist on my system.
So when I use Alias, list is
LS L. Well then I can type
the list command to execute the LS
L. Let's do a Control L again
and let me use Sleep 600, which
is going to do nothing for 10
minutes, but it will keep my
console busy. Well, I don't like that.
So I'm going to use Control
C to quit it and echo.
This is some text and oh boy, I forgot something. Well
then I'm going to use Ctrl A to move my cursor to
the beginning or Control E to move my cursor to the
end. And if I change my mind and I don't want to
run this command at all, Control U will wipe the current
command line. And that's the best shortcuts that you should know about.